<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nathan&#39;s Blog </title>
    <link>https://nndd91.github.io/hugoblog/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Nathan</author>
    <rights>(C) 2017</rights>
    <updated>2017-05-13 17:45:28 &#43;0800 SGT</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>A new way of Web development</title>
          <link>https://nndd91.github.io/hugoblog/post/a-new-way-of-dev/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 17:45:28 SGT</pubDate>
          <author>Nathan</author>
          <guid>https://nndd91.github.io/hugoblog/post/a-new-way-of-dev/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will write about my thoughts on generating site using Hugo as a web developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I have not used Hugo much but it seems like if you know how to customize it, you can really use it to make all sorts of website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the value of the site, it seems like sites generated using hugo will be hard to sell due to the poor usability of the tool. This is because the people that finish developing the website may not be the people that updates it constantly. Eg. Developers can create the wordpress platform, but the people that are using it the most are people that are in charge of content such as editors, marketing team etc. So usability is a huge hurdle for Hugo to overcome. I think an improvement to Hugo would maybe be an app with an improved user interface that allows user to update post or create the site without ever touching the command line. That would then gives us developers value to use this to build our sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ease of updating the site is also an issue. For sites like wordpress, you can easily update the page by going to the admin menu, edit it and click the save button. But for Hugo site, you need to edit the page, save it, generate the hugo site, overwrite the server hugo site with the newly generated files before it is done. This creates alot of trouble especially if you update your site several times a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So who are Hugo good for now? I think for companies that needs a fast loading webpage and do not mind hiring a tech savy editor. Why do I say that, because the person still really needs to be comfortable with using git, or being able to access the server using ftp and copying the public folder generated and overwriting it to update content. People that are not tech savvy might run into problems and when they cant fix the problems, site might go down or they might even destroy the source files. So definitely place Hugo sites in the hands of people that knows what they are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also if you need to generate a site that rarely needs update, then truthfully you can just hire a designer to build a static page using html css, etc. You really do not need Hugo if all you need is a static webpage that does not need updating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of user interface may make it hard for customer to update the site in future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>First thoughts about using Hugo</title>
          <link>https://nndd91.github.io/hugoblog/post/first-review/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 17:18:01 SGT</pubDate>
          <author>Nathan</author>
          <guid>https://nndd91.github.io/hugoblog/post/first-review/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo, a fast and modern static site engine. When I first heard of it, it seems like a good idea. It still is! But after using it you quickly realise its not as perfect as it seems. You quickly realise that Hugo is built for the more tech savy users and lack any form of guidance for those less tech savvy. No doubt they have a great documentation, but users nowadays are too impatient to flip through pages of documentation to get their first site up. A lack of user interface also means that user have to pick up the command line and also learn a little bit of programming to customize their page. Other CMS like the wordpress are so intuitive that user can get by without ever learning how to code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo is fast. Not having dynamic content means we can use the HTTP server for what it is meant to do - focus on delivering content. The website boast that a page with 5000 posts can be loaded in seconds. Furthermore, being a static site, you will be able to find host very easily. This will also help to cut down your cost as static site host are usually much cheaper than host that support other kind of server technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customizability is also there if you know some basic programming. You can also easily customize all parts of Hugo to make it create the perfect site that you want. But that is the catch, you really need to know programming. If you do not know, then there is no user interface that can help you to customize it easily. But I suppose there are a great number of themes that can be easily downloaded and placed in your themes folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It definitely feels good to be able to edit your post offline using your favourite text editor. Even notepad if that is your kind of thing. But the truth is, I kind of miss all the tools that wordpress provides. Eg I can easily attached an image by clicking on the add the image button. As for Hugo, actually I do not know how to attach an image here. I tried to do alittle bit of formatting such as making a list, but I have to search online on how to use markdown to format my page. Granted that markdown is pretty easy to learn, but I just kind of miss the great user interface provided by wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No doubt it takes a different approach to the modern web development but we must also realise that not everyone is a coder. If speed is really your utmost importance, then by all means, Hugo is definitely the right way to go. However, if you want to be able to edit your post easily, using the great many tools that allows you to tag, attach images without learning how to code, then you are better off using something else such as Wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast Delivery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to find host, its just a simple static websie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High Customizability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Able to do editing offline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Needs to be proficient and comfortable with using the command line, Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not as intuitive to set up as compared to eg Wordpress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>My first post here</title>
          <link>https://nndd91.github.io/hugoblog/post/first-post/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 17:00:38 SGT</pubDate>
          <author>Nathan</author>
          <guid>https://nndd91.github.io/hugoblog/post/first-post/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first post for this hugo blog. I find the concept very smart and interesting. Even though it was supposed to be a technique that was used since the 1990s. I guess I am probaby just too used to the modern way of doing things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
